The bpx-palm-xx-palm-lib-member contains the parameters used to influence user logon,
the maximum number of active processes, file handling and storage requirements
for the zos-unix-system-services environment.
These parameter values apply to all Unix processes in the system.
Many bpx-palm-xx-parameter values can be modified without re-initializing the system
using either the set-omvs or the set-omvs equals operator commands.
You can control the amount of resources that are consumed by individual zos-unix-system-services
users. bpx-palm-xx is still used to define resource limits, but it should be used to
set the limits to the values required by the majority of users.
The rackf-omvs segment of the user profile can be used to define the resource limits for
users that have higher requirements than the limits defined in bpx-palm-xx.
The add-user and alt-user commands can be used to specify or adjust the resource limits
for an individual user. This diagram illustrates the read-only ZFS HFS data sharing which was the
only supported file system data sharing for zos. ZOS provides support for simultaneous read-write
access to the same ZFS or HFS file system across instances of Unix system services running
on multiple ZOS images in a Sysplex. Only one Sysplex system owns a given file system.
Across system coupling facility or XCF services are used during the processing of shared
file systems in the Sysplex. With shared ZFS and HFS, all file systems that are mounted
by a system participating in the shared HFS are available to all participating systems.
In other words, once a file system is mounted by a participating system,
that file system is accessible by any other participating system.
Function shipping means that a request is forwarded to the owning system and the
response is returned back to the requester through XCF communications.
A file system can be mounted Sysplex aware or non-Sysplex aware.
When a file system is mounted Sysplex aware, it means that the file system is locally
mounted on every system when the PFS is capable of handling a local mount on every system,
that is the PFS is running Sysplex aware, and therefore file requests are handled by the local
PFS. All read-only mounted file systems are always mounted Sysplex aware.
HFS read-write mounted file systems are always mounted non-Sysplex aware. This means that
file requests from non-ZOS Unix owning systems are always function shipped by ZOS Unix to the
ZOS Unix owning system where the file system is locally mounted and the IO is actually done.
To enable ZFS Sysplex aware on a file system basis,
specify Sysplex equals file sys in IOE PRMXX or IOE FS PRM.
You can specify it in a shared IOE PRMXX, IOE FS PRM and each system picks up the specification
in a rolling IPL. This means that USS sends all file requests directly to the local CFS
physical file system. CFS direct IO is a performance
improvement for the shared file system environment using ZFS read-write Sysplex aware file systems.
ZFS direct IO enhances support for ZFS read-write Sysplex aware file systems.
CFS can directly read and write Sysplex aware file systems from all systems in the shared
file system environment. This makes file system ownership much less important.
If the ZFS file system is mounted Sysplex aware, any client ZFS can directly access the file
system for reading and writing data and partially also reading metadata. So any user or
application can exploit the functionality for ZFS read-write Sysplex aware file systems.
In this case, the Sysplex aware file system FS2 is ZFS owned by SY2 and is being directly
accessed from SY1 and SY3. Ownership will no longer move because we only keep count of metadata
update. The system route is a ZFS HFS data set that is used as the Sysplex wide route.
This ZFS HFS data set must be mounted read-write. Only one Sysplex route is allowed for all systems
participating in shared HFS. Directories in the system specified HFS data set are used as mount
points specifically for slash etc slash var slash temp and slash dev. And that wraps up this lecture
series on COS Unix system services. I hope you found it useful and thank you for watching.